<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33053381</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0712</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>889</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Treatment for COVID-19: An overview.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>173644</StartPage><MedlinePgn>173644</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.173644</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0014-2999(20)30736-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is an infectious disease caused by coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) that causes a severe acute respiratory syndrome, a characteristic hyperinflammatory response, vascular damage, microangiopathy, angiogenesis and widespread thrombosis. Four stages of COVID-19 have been identified: the first stage is characterised by upper respiratory tract infection; the second by the onset of dyspnoea and pneumonia; the third by a worsening clinical scenario dominated by a cytokine storm and the consequent hyperinflammatory state; and the fourth by death or recovery. Currently, no treatment can act specifically against the SARS-CoV-2 infection. Based on the pathological features and different clinical phases of COVID-19, particularly in patients with moderate to severe COVID-19, the classes of drugs used are antiviral agents, inflammation inhibitors/antirheumatic drugs, low molecular weight heparins, plasma, and hyperimmune immunoglobulins. During this emergency period of the COVID-19 outbreak, clinical researchers are using and testing a variety of possible treatments. Based on these premises, this review aims to discuss the most updated pharmacological treatments to effectively act against the SARS-CoV-2 infection and support researchers and clinicians in relation to any current and future developments in curing COVID-19 patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#169; 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stasi</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Unit, Tuscany Regional Health Agency, Florence, Italy; Department of Experimental and Clinical Medicine, Careggi University Hospital, Florence, Italy. Electronic address: cristina.stasi@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fallani</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Unit, Tuscany Regional Health Agency, Florence, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Voller</LastName><ForeName>Fabio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Unit, Tuscany Regional Health Agency, Florence, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silvestri</LastName><ForeName>Caterina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Unit, Tuscany Regional Health Agency, Florence, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1254354</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2999</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antirheumatic drugs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low molecular weight heparins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7548059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.173644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0014-2999(20)30736-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Accorsi P., Berti P., de Angelis V., De Silvestro G., Mascaretti L., Ostuni A. &#8221;Position paper&#8221; sulla produzione di plasma iperimmune da utilizzare nella terapia della malattia da SARS-CoV2. 2020. http://www.emaferesi.it/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Convalescent-Plasma-SIMTI_SIDEM-1.pdf Available at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  BARICIVID-19 study: MultiCentre, randomised, Phase IIa clinical trial evaluating efficacy and tolerability of Baricitinib as add-on treatment of patients with COVID-19 compared to standard therapy. Sperimentazioni cliniche. 2020 https://www.aifa.gov.it/sperimentazioni-cliniche-covid-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  COVID-19 - AIFA autorizza nuovo studio clinico con tocilizumab. 2020 b. https://www.aifa.gov.it/web/guest/-/covid-19-aifa-autorizza-nuovo-studio-clinico-con-tocilizumab</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  . 2020 c. Studio randomizzato multicentrico in aperto sull&#8217;efficacia della somministrazione precoce del Tocilizumab in pazienti affetti da polmonite da COVID-19.https://www.aifa.gov.it/documents/20142/1123276/studio_RE_Toci_17.06.2020.pdf/c32ed144-ce26-d673-6e4d-11d5d0d84836</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  Plasma: ISS e AIFA, studio nazionale per valutarne l'efficacia. 2020 h. https://www.aifa.gov.it/-/plasma-iss-e-aifa-studio-nazionale-per-valutarne-l-efficacia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  Eparine a basso peso molecolare nei pazienti adulti con COVID-19. 2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/documents/20142/1123276/Eparine_Basso_Peso_Molecolare_11.04.2020.pdf/e30686fb-3f5e-32c9-7c5c-951cc40872f7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  COVID-19 - comunicazione EMA su clorochina e idrossiclorochina. 2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/-/covid-19-comunicazione-ema-su-clorochina-e-idrossiclorochina</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  AIFA sospende l&#8217;autorizzazione all&#8217;utilizzo di idrossiclorochina per il trattamento del COVID-19 al di fuori degli studi clinici. 2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/web/guest/-/aifa-sospende-l-autorizzazione-all-utilizzo-di-idrossiclorochina-per-il-trattamento-del-covid-19-al-di-fuori-degli-studi-clinici</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco  Idrossiclorochina nella terapia dei pazienti adulti con COVID-19. 2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/documents/20142/1123276/idrossiclorochina_29.05.2020.pdf/3958aea0-5a5f-2d05-b1f6-034dbe28ce2a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigel J.H., Tomashek K.M., Dodd L.E., Mehta A.K., Zingman B.S., Kalil A.C., Hohmann E., Chu H.Y., Luetkemeyer A., Kline S., Lopez de Castilla D., Finberg R.W., Dierberg K., Tapson V., Hsieh L., Patterson T.F., Paredes R., Sweeney D.A., Short W.R., Touloumi G., Lye D.C., Ohmagari N., Oh M.D., Ruiz-Palacios G.M., Benfield T., F&#228;tkenheuer G., Kortepeter M.G., Atmar R.L., Creech C.B., Lundgren J., Babiker A.G., Pett S., Neaton J.D., Burgess T.H., Bonnett T., Green M., Makowski M., Osinusi A., Nayak S., Lane H.C., ACTT-1 Study Group Members Remdesivir for the treatment of Covid-19 - preliminary report. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020 doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2007764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2007764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantini F., Niccoli L., Nannini C., Matarrese D., Natale M.E.D., Lotti P., Aquilini D., Landini G., Cimolato B., Pietro M.A.D., Trezzi M., Stobbione P., Frausini G., Navarra A., Nicastri E., Sotgiu G., Goletti D.J. Beneficial impact of Baricitinib in COVID-19 moderate pneumonia; multicentre study. J. Infect. 2020;S0163&#8211;4453(20) doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.06.052. 30433-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.06.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7313480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B., Wang Y., Wen D., Liu W., Wang J., Fan G., Ruan L., Song B., Cai Y., Wei M., Li X., Xia J., Chen N., Xiang J., Yu T., Bai T., Xie X., Zhang L., Li C., Yuan Y., Chen H., Li H., Huang H., Tu S., Gong F., Liu Y., Wei Y., Dong C., Zhou F., Gu X., Xu J., Liu Z., Zhang Y., Li H., Shang L., Wang K., Li K., Zhou X., Dong X., Qu Z., Lu S., Hu X., Ruan S., Luo S., Wu J., Peng L., Cheng F., Pan L., Zou J., Jia C., Wang J., Liu X., Wang S., Wu X., Ge Q., He J., Zhan H., Qiu F., Guo L., Huang C., Jaki T., Hayden F.G., Horby P.W., Zhang D., Wang C. A trial of lopinavir-ritonavir in adults hospitalized with severe Covid-19. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:1787&#8211;1799. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2001282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7121492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32187464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W., Zhang B., Su H., Li J., Zhao Y., Xie X., Jin Z., Peng J., Liu F., Li C., Li Y., Bai F., Wang H., Cheng X., Cen X., Hu S., Yang X., Wang J., Liu X., Xiao G., Jiang H., Rao Z., Zhang L.K., Xu Y., Yang H., Liu H. Structure-based design of antiviral drug candidates targeting the SARS-CoV-2 main protease. Science. 2020 doi: 10.1126/science.abb4489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abb4489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Documents - AIFA Adaptive Randomized trial for therapy of Corona virus disease 2019 at home with oral antivirals (ARCO-Home study) 2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/documents/20142/1131319/covid-19_sperimentazioni_in_corso_09.05.2020.pdf/9d46f533-7406-8f7c-5e34-c119f7087d65 Accessed 7 May.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Executive summary &#8211; Agenzia Italiana del Farmaco.  2020. https://www.aifa.gov.it/documents/20142/1127901/executive_summary_Toci_Nazionale.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA News Release Coronavirus (COVID-19) update: FDA coordinates national effort to develop blood-related therapies for COVID-19. 2020. https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-coordinates-national-effort-develop-blood-related-therapies-covid-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredi M., Cavazzana I., Moschetti L., Andreoli L., Franceschini F., on behalf of the Brescia Rheumatology COVID-19 Study Group  COVID-19 in patients with rheumatic diseases in northern Italy: a single-centre observational and case&#8211;control study. 2020. https://www.thelancet.com/action/showPdf?pii=S2665-9913%2820%2930169-7 18 June 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman J.D., Lye D.C.B., Hui D.S., Marks K.M., Bruno R., Montejano R., Spinner C.D., Galli M., Ahn M.Y., Nahass R.G., Chen Y.S., SenGupta D., Hyland R.H., Osinusi A.O., Cao H., Blair C., Wei X., Gaggar A., Brainard D.M., Towner W.J., Mu&#241;oz J., Mullane K.M., Marty F.M., Tashima K.T., Diaz G., Subramanian A., GS-US-540-5773 Investigators Remdesivir for 5 or 10 Days in patients with severe Covid-19. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020 doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2015301. 2020, 10.1056/NEJMoa2015301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2015301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grein J., Ohmagari N., Shin D., Diaz G., Asperges E., Castagna A., Feldt T., Green G., Green M.L., Lescure F.X., Nicastri E., Oda R., Yo K., Quiros-Roldan E., Studemeister A., Redinski J., Ahmed S., Bernett J., Chelliah D., Chen D., Chihara S., Cohen S.H., Cunningham J., D'Arminio Monforte A., Ismail S., Kato H., Lapadula G., L'Her E., Maeno T., Majumder S., Massari M., Mora-Rillo M., Mutoh Y., Nguyen D., Verweij E., Zoufaly A., Osinusi A.O., DeZure A., Zhao Y., Zhong L., Chokkalingam A., Elboudwarej E., Telep L., Timbs L., Henne I., Sellers S., Cao H., Tan S.K., Winterbourne L., Desai P., Mera R., Gaggar A., Myers R.P., Brainard D.M., Childs R., Flanigan T. Compassionate use of remdesivir for patients with severe Covid-19. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:2327&#8211;2336. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2007016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2007016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guaraldi G., Meschiari M., Cozzi-Lepri A., Milic J., Tonelli R., Menozzi M., Franceschini E., Cuomo G., Orlando G., Borghi V., Santoro A., Di Gaetano M., Puzzolante C., Carli F., Bedini A., Corradi L., Fantini R., Castaniere I., Tabb&#236; L., Girardis M., Tedeschi S., Giannella M., Bartoletti M., Pascale R., Dolci G., Brugioni L., Pietrangelo A., Cossarizza A., Pea F., Clini E., Salvarani C., Massari M., Viale P.L., Mussini C. Tocilizumab in patients with severe COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Rheumatol. 2020;2:e474&#8211;e484. doi: 10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30173-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30173-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gul M.H., Htun Z.M., Shaukat N., Imran M., Khan A. Potential specific therapies in COVID-19. Ther. Adv. Respir. Dis. 2020;14 doi: 10.1177/1753466620926853. 1753466620926853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1753466620926853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RECOVERY Collaborative Group, Horby P., Lim W.S., Emberson J.R., Mafham M., Bell J.L., Linsell L., Staplin N., Brightling C., Ustianowski A., Elmahi E., Prudon B., Green C., Felton T., Chadwick D., Rege K., Fegan C., Chappell L.C., Faust S.N., Jaki T., Jeffery K., Montgomery A., Rowan K., Juszczak E., Baillie J.K., Haynes R., Landray M.J. Dexamethasone in Hospitalized Patients with Covid-19 - Preliminary Report. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jul 17 doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2021436. NEJMoa2021436, Epub ahead of print. PMID: 32678530; PMCID: PMC7383595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2021436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32678530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Wang Y., Li X., Ren L., Zhao J., Hu Y. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#8211;506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isidori A.M., Arnaldi G., Boscaro M., Falorni A., Giordano C., Giordano R., Pivonello R., Pofi R., Hasenmajer V., Venneri M.A., Sbardella E., Simeoli C., Scaroni C., Lenzi A. COVID-19 infection and glucocorticoids: update from the Italian Society of Endocrinology Expert Opinion on steroid replacement in adrenal insufficiency. J. Endocrinol. Invest. 2020;43:1141&#8211;1147. doi: 10.1007/s40618-020-01266-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40618-020-01266-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King A., Vail A., O'Leary C., Hannan C., Brough D., Patel H., Galea J., Ogungberno K., Wright M., Pathmanaban O., Hulme S., Allan S. Anakinra in COVID-19: important considerations for clinical trials. Lancet Rheumatol. 2020;2:e379&#8211;381. doi: 10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30160-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(20)30160-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Q.X., Li Y., Peng J., Huang Y., Xu D. Antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2 in patients with COVID-19. Nat. Med. 2020;26:845&#8211;848. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0897-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0897-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matricardi P., Dal Negro R., Nisini R. The first, holistic immunological model of COVID&#8208;19: implications for prevention, diagnosis, and public health measures. Paediatric Allergy and Immunology. 2020 doi: 10.1111/pai.13271. 10.1111/pai.13271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pai.13271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehra M.R., Desai S.S., Ruschitzka F., Patel A.N. RETRACTED: hydroxychloroquine or chloroquine with or without a macrolide for treatment of COVID-19: a multinational registry analysis. Lancet. 2020;S0140&#8211;6736(20):31180&#8211;31186. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31180-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31180-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32450107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P., McAuley D.F., Brown M., Sanchez E., Tattersall R.S., Manson J.J., on behalf of the HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395:1033&#8211;1034. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomised evaluation of COVID-19 therapy. 2020. https://www.recoverytrial.net/ Available at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson P., Griffin I., Tucker C., Smith D., Oechsle O., Phelan A., Rawling M., Savory E., Stebbing J. Baricitinib as potential treatment for 2019-nCoV acute respiratory disease. Lancet. 2020;395:e30&#8211;e31. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30304-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30304-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7137985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32032529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C., Wang Z., Zhao F., Yang Y., Li J., Yuan J., Wang F., Li D., Yang M., Xing L., Wei J., Xiao H., Yang Y., Qu J., Qing L., Chen L., Xu Z., Peng L., Li Y., Zheng H., Chen F., Huang K., Jiang Y., Liu D., Zhang Z., Liu Y., Liu L. Treatment of 5 critically ill patients with COVID-19 with convalescent plasma. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2020;323:1582&#8211;1589. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.4783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N., Bai H., Chen X., Gong J., Li D., Sun Z. Anticoagulant treatment is associated with decreased mortality in severe coronavirus disease 2019 patients with coagulopathy. J. Thromb. Haemostasis. 2020;18:1094&#8211;1099. doi: 10.1111/jth.14817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jth.14817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. S. National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrial.gov  FLARE: favipiravir +/- lopinavir: a RCT of early antivirals (FLARE) 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04499677</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. S. National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrial.gov  Trial of Early Therapies During Non-hospitalized Outpatient Window for COVID-19 (TREATNOW) 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04372628?term=antiviral+agents%2C+early+phase&amp;cond=Covid19&amp;draw=6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. S. National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrial.gov  Efficacy and safety of emapalumab and anakinra in reducing hyperinflammation and respiratory distress in patients with COVID-19 infection. 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT043240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. S. National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrial.gov  Convalescent plasma vs. Standard plasma for COVID-19. 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04344535?cond=NCT04344535&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valk S.J., Piechotta V., Chai K.L., Doree C., Monsef I., Wood E.M., Lamikanra A., Kimber C., McQuilten Z., So-Osman C., Estcourt L.J., Skoetz N. Convalescent plasma or hyperimmune immunoglobulin for people with COVID&#8208;19: a rapid review. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2020;5:CD013600. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD013600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD013600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Solidarity  clinical trial for COVID-19 treatments. 2020. https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/global-research-on-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/solidarity-clinical-trial-for-covid-19-treatments</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization WHO updates clinical care guidance with corticosteroid recommendations. 2020 b. https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/who-updates-clinical-care-guidance-with-corticosteroid-recommendations</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>